Guide to the Sarah Elbert papers, 1968-1976.
Elbert, Sarah papers, 1968-1976
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Sarah Elbert papers, 1968-1976.
2914
Sarah Elbert.
4 cubic ft., 6 reels movie film, 6 VHS cassettes, 32 CDs, 4 DVDs, 55 tape recordings.
Film, videotapes, audiotapes, cd, articles, notes, clippings, and leaflets.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers of Sarah Elbert (Cornell University Class of 1965), who initiated "The Streets Belong to the People" as a part of her study of student radicalism and counterculture.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Sarah Elbert (Cornell University Class of 1965) initiated "The Streets Belong to the People" as a part of her study of student radicalism and counterculture. The film crew consisted of herself, Ralph Diamant (filmmaker), James Sheldon (Students for a Democratic Society member), Phyllis Black (Chicago student), Michael Wright (Chicago student and S.D.S. member), Phyllis Cutter, and Susan Schultze.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
"The Streets Belong to the People", 16 mm. film, videotapes (different versions) and unedited footage of movie film made in Chicago during the Democratic National Convention, August 1968. Also, articles, notes, clippings, leaflets, radical newspapers' tape recordings, movie film and documents related to the production of the film. Includes film, recorded interviews, and records related to the Democratic National Convention; the National Farm Workers and Cesar Chavez; the Starr King Divinity School; members of a Cambridge, Massachusetts commune; an S.D.S. meeting, study class, and rally; a meeting of Ithaca Housing; and the March 1967 confrontation at Willard Straight Hall (Cornell University) over draft card burning. Includes interviews with Jeff Jones, Paul Krassner, Robert Traill Spence Lowell, Jr., Rennie Davis, David Whitley Dellinger, Dick Gregory, Vic Bell, Allen Ginsberg, Ralph David Abernathy, Norman Mailer, Tom Hayden, David Burak, Bruce Dancis, Daniel Berrigan, Jerry Brown, and Eugene McCarthy. Also, Elbert's manuscript notes and correspondence concerning publication of Louisa May Alcott's previously unpublished novella Diana and Persis and Alcott's Work: A Story of Experience.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Elbert, Sarah.; Abernathy, Ralph, 1926-; Alcott, Louisa May, 1832-1888. -- Diana and Persis.; Alcott, Louisa May, 1832-1888. -- Work, a story of experience.; Bell, Vic.; Berrigan, Daniel.; Brown, Jerry, 1938-; Burak, David, 1945-; Chavez, Cesar, 1927-; Dancis, Bruce.; Davis, Rennie.; Dellinger, David W.; Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-; Gregory, Dick.; Hayden, Tom.; Jones, Jeff.; Krassner, Paul.; Lowell, Robert Traill Spence, 1917-; Mailer, Norman.; McCarthy, Eugene J., 1916-; Pecot, Marcelle.; National Farm Workers Association.; Starr King Divinity School.; Students for a Democratic Society (U.S.)
Titles:
Streets belong to the people.
Subjects:
Radicalism.; Students--Political activity.; Student movements.; Draft resisters.; Novelists, American.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Protest movements.
Places:
United States--Politics and government,--1963-1969.
Form and Genre Terms:
Motion pictures.; Interviews.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Masters of "The Streets Belong to the People" not to be used
NOTES
Includes collection #2964, New Left and underground periodicals. Mainly having belonged to Ralph and Sarah Diamant
Videocassette provided by Marcelle Pecot of out-takes of "The Streets Belong to the People" (V-208).
Videocassette "Chicago 1968" (V-238) also includes scenes from "The Streets Belong to the People."
DVD copied from Reels F-159, F-160, F161 and F162.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Source Files
Box 1, Former collection #2964 Box 1
Collection #2914
Former Collection #2964
Series II. Periodicals
Box 1, Former collection #2964 Box 1
Collection #2914
Former Collection #2964
Series III. Film Documents
Box 1
Series IV. Tape Recordings
Box 2
Chicago Democratic Convention, August 25-29, 1968
Student Radicalism
Delano, California Interviews
Series V: Transcripts Made from Reel to Reel Recordings
Box 2
Series VI. Film (masters, not to be used)
Boxes 4 & 5
Series VII. Video
Boxes 4 & 5
Series VIII. CDs and DVDs
Boxes 5
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Source Files
  Contains articles, clippings, leaflets, and drawings on radicalism
  - Collection #2914
    - Berman, Maddey. (Students for McCarthy) "Alienation and Music: Simon and Garfunckel." (Folder 1, Box 1)
    - The Black University Report to the National Conference of the Association of Afro-American Educators; Poussaint, Alfred F. "The Negro American: His Self-Image and Integration.", June 9, 1968 (Folder 2, Box 1)
    - Blumenthal, Ralph. "Berliner Student Commune." N.Y. Times clipping (Folder 3, Box 1)
    - Cornell Activism articles (Folder 4, Box 1)
    - Dylan (Folder 5, Box 1)
    - Encounter, T-Groups, Esalen (Folder 6, Box 1)
    - The Family, clippings and photocopy (Folder 7, Box 1)
    - Goldstein, Vic. (Students for a Democratic Society) 'Arch '69 drawings, including Radical's notebook (Folder 8, Box 1)
    - Goodman, Paul. "Freedom and Learning: The Need for Choice," "The New Aristocrats." (Folder 9, Box 1)
    - Heckman, J. Cambridge Commune clipping from The Justice, November 13, 1968. (Folder 10, Box 1)
    - Heintz, Jeff. "Norman Mailor: A Polemical." (Folder 11, Box 1)
    - Kelsey, Herb. "Going to the Army is some Real Serious Shit." (Folder 12, Box 1)
    - Lefebre, Ludwig B. "Human and Extrahuman Partnership," Psychology Today, November 1968 (Folder 13, Box 1)
    - May Day Tactical Manual (Folder 14, Box 1)
    - Marshall, Chip. "Our Children Have Come Home." (Folder 15, Box 1)
    - Nowogrodzki, Richard. "Cornell Authors." (Folder 16, Box 1)
    - Oglesby, Carl. "World Revolution and the American Containment." (Folder 17, Box 1)
    - Slater, R. Guiseppi. "Canadian Crisis: A Descriptive Evaluation of Quebec Student Unrest." (Folder 18, Box 1)
    - Speiser, R. "Geschichte des Nachtwächters - Overview Cornell." (Folder 19, Box 1)
    - Student Activism Photocopies (Folder 20, Box 1)
    - S.D.S. article. U.S. News and World Report. (Folder 21, Box 1)
    - Students for Educational Transformation proposal (Folder 22, Box 1)
    - "Student Revolutionaries Unite." (Folder 23, Box 1)
    - "The Streets Belong to the People." (Folder 24, Box 1)
    - Village Voice, Paris Revolt, June 6. (Folder 25, Box 1)
    - Why Those Students are Protesting", May 3, 1968 (Folder 26, Box 1)
  - Former Collection #2964
    - Token Learning: A Study of Women's Higher Education in America published by the National Organization for Women (NOW), November 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - Law and Disorder: The Chicago Convention and Its Aftermath, 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - Esalen Programs brochure, 1969 (Box #2964-1)
    - The Phantom - comic book, Undated (Box #2964-1)
    - Flyers and handouts for the demonstrations at the 1968 Democratic Convention, c. August 1968 (Box #2964-1, Folder 3)
    - Summer of Support, April 1968 (Box #2964-1, Folder 4)
      Effort to reach out to military communities
    - Flyers for Baltimore related events, July & October 1968 (Box #2964-1, Folder 5)
    - Still photographs from Chicago, c. August 1968 (Box #2964-1, Folder 6)
    - Bulletins of Cornell Program in Oral History, December 1968, December 1969 (Box #2964-1, Folder 7)
    - Going to the Army is Some Real Serious Shit Zine, Undated (Box #2964-1, Folder 8)
    - Father John Dee (of the Singing Priest and Mary) newsletter., c. December 1969 (Box #2964-1, Folder 9)
    - Oversized still photograph, Undated (Box #2964-1, Folder 10)
- Series II. Periodicals
  - Collection #2914
    - Avatar, American Colony Press, c. June 1968 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - April 24, Washington, D.C., Spring 1971 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - The Chicago Maroon, Vol. 77 no. 5, August 30, 1968. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - The Chicago Seed, Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - (Note: Chicago Tribune, Section 1A, August 25, 1968 was discarded from the collection.)
    - Date-Line-Ithaca, Glad Day Press, nos. 46-47, 49-51, June 26-July 31, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Free Student, no. 5. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - New Left Notes, Chicago, Vol. 3 nos. 24, 25., August 5, 12, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - The Old Mole, Cambridge, MA, Vol. 1, no. 4., November 16, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Peace and Freedom National Organizer, Undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Quicksilver Times Vol. III, Jan. 16-26, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Rat Subterranean News, Vol. 1, no. 14, annotated (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - The Realist, No. 82, September 1968 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Record, Antioch College, Vol. 23 nos. 25, 27-28, 30-33, 35-36, 38, 41, 44 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Record, Antioch College, Vol. 24 nos. 1-5, 16-18. (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - The Scimitar, Ithaca N.Y., Vol. 1 no. 1. (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Spring Movement, Washington D.C., April 8, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Viet Report, October 1965 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Former Collection #2964
    - The Antiochian, Vol. 40, no. 4, January 1969 (Box #2964-1)
    - Avatar, Vol. 2, no. 3, July 4-18, 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - Challenge The Revolutionary Newspaper - Progressive Labor Party monthly, Undated (Box #2964-1)
    - Cheetah, Vol. 1, no. 1, October 1967 (Box #2964-1)
      Missing cover.
    - The Chicago Maroon, Vol. 76, no.6, August-September 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - The Chicago Seed, Vol. 2, no. 5, 13, 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - The Chicago Sun Times, Vol. 21, no. 178, August 27-29, 1968 (Box #2964-1)
      Incomplete. News on the Democratic Convention.
    - Congressional Record, Vol 114, no. 142, 143, 145, September 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - The Cornell Daily Sun, Vol. 85, no. 75, February 5, 1969 (Box #2964-1)
    - Dateline=Ithaca, No. 58, October 16, 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - Demokratia, Vol. 1, no. 5, September 1968 (Box #2964-1)
      Sponsored by the Union of Greeks and American for Democracy in Greece.
    - The East Village Other, Vol. 3, no. 2, 28, 40, December 1967-September 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - Esquire, Vol. 70, no. 2, 6, August & December 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - Esquire, Vol. 68, no. 40, October 6 & 7, 1968 (Box #2964-1)
      Incomplete.
    - First Issue, January & April 1968 (Box #2964-1)
      Publication based in Ithaca
    - Fortnight, Vol. 1, no. 5, February 5, 1969 (Box #2964-1)
    - Guardian, Vol. 20, no. 7; Vol. 21, no. 5, August & November 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - Gramma, Year 2, no. 34, August 1967 (Box #2964-1)
      "Official organ of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of Cuba"
    - Handwriting on the Wall, no. 2 (by S.D.S.), Undated (Box #2964-1)
    - Harper's Magazine, March 1968 (Box #2964-1)
      With "The Steps of the Pentagon" by Norman Mailer
    - Life, Vol. 65, no. 3, 16, July & October 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - The Mother of Voices, Vol. 1, Issue 6, c. February 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - Newsweek, September 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - The New York Review of Books, Vol. 11, no. 1, July 11, 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - New York Times, August 26, September 4, 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - New York Times Magazine, June & August 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - Psychology Today, Vol. 2, no. 4, 7, September & December 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - Ramparts, Vol. 5, no. Vol. 6, no. 7, 8, 11, 12; Vol. 7, no. 2, 3, May 1967 - August 1968 (Box #2964-1)
      One issue undated, missing cover
    - The Ramparts wall posters (3), August 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - Record, Antioch College, Vol. 24 nos. 10, 14, 20, 21, October & December 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - The Scimitar, Vol. 1, no. 5, 6, October-November 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - Summer by the Chicago Maroon, Vol. 77, no. 5, August 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - Time, Vol. 92, no. 10, September 6, 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - Veterans Stars and Stripes for Peace, Vol 1, no. 8, August-September 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - The Village Voice, Vol. 13, no. 38, 52; Vol. 14, no. 2, October 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - Washington Free Press, Vol. 2, no. 22, 24, 25, 26, 27, January-March 1968 (Box #2964-1)
    - What's New, August 21, 1968 (Box #2964-1)
      Official personnel publication of the United States Penitentiary in Lewisberg, PA.
    - Newspaper Clippings, c. August - December 1968 (Box #2964-1, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper Clippings on University of Massachusetts demonstrations, November 1968 (Box #2964-1, Folder 2)
- Series III. Film documents
  - Project proposal (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Chicago notes (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Film screenplay (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Report, grace notes (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Questionnaire from the Feb. 20 showing of the film (Box 1, Folder 48-51)
  - Clippings (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Lerner critique on draft of Work introduction for Schocken, October 1976 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Intro to Work, Schocken ed. (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Diana & Persis original manuscript (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Diana & Persis first draft (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Diana & Persis (Box 1, Folder 57-58)
  - Work: Domestic Feminism & the Problem of Cultural Hegemony. (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Dissertation prospectus copy & notes, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Work (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Chapter on Work: A Story of Experience. (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Introduction to Schocken ed. Work (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Diana & Persis manuscript by Louisa A. Alcott. (Box 1, Folder 64-66)
  - "Moods" [?] - manuscript (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Series IV. Tape Recordings
  - Subseries 1. Chicago Democratic Convention, August 25-29, 1968
    These are mainly reel to reel tapes (noted when otherwise). Tape titles here reflect what is written on the outside of the tape boxes
    - 1st half com. 7 - lost, 5 1/2 minutes. Continuation on 6B, August 1968; tr-268-1 (Box 2)
      Use CD-45-46
    - 2nd half Gov. bot tape (...) no identification number recorded by Gray., August 28, 1968; tr-268-1 (Box 2)
      1. 18th & Michigan.
      2. Negotiation between Peck & Reardon, Elrod on 8/28/68 at 5:15.
    - Tape B and Thursday afternoon, Bother Jonathan, Jeff Jones, Paul Krassner, Tom Hayden., August 29, 1968; tr-268-2 (Box 2)
    - Vic Bell, McCarthy, Robert Lowell, Poem on Columbia. Side 2: R. Diamant account of "Battle of Michigan Ave.", tr-268-3 (Box 2)
    - Shirley Lens, interview: Phylis Cutter, immediate recall of events in Grant Park., August 27, 1968; tr-268-4 (Box 2)
    - Bacia Gordon, Susan Schultze, interviewer. Immediate recall of events in Grant Park., August 27, 1968; tr-268-5 (Box 2)
      Use CD-21
    - David Spzek, John Levy, Ken McMillan, interviewer: Susan Schultze, August 1968; tr-268-6 (Box 2)
    - Susan Roupp, Father Daniel Turner, Jerry Dean Schmidt, interviewer, Susan Schultze, August 1968; tr-268-7 (Box 2)
    - Tape #5, Hayden, Rennie David, Delinger - "Create many Chi's", etc., August 1968; tr-268-8 (Box 2)
    - 2nd half of Reel 3 (202) Grand Park; #2 Can 4 - very important(end of Barrdell?), August 28, 1968; tr-268-9 (Box 2)
      Use CD-47-48
    - 32 short clips. Starts with McCarthy campaign and includes clips of Julian Bond and Gore Vidal, August 1968; tr-268-10 (Box 2)
      Use CD-49
    - Mainly sounds - Wind, tinkling, sirens, chants etc., August 1968; tr-268-11 (Box 2)
    - Rubber band thumps, deadened thumps, Peabody modulated, bridge drones, Free Hayden, etc., August 1968; tr-268-12 (Box 2)
      Use CD-50
    - Tape #1 Steve Simmons for Hubert Humphrey. McCarthy headquarters, 2 interviews, August 25, 1968.; tr-268-13 (Box 2)
    - Tape #2 Park & Demonstration Sunday afternoon. Chicago McCarthy interview, several good chants, park music (DU)., August 25, 1968; tr-268-14 (Box 2)
      Use CD-51
    - Tape #3 Night - Yippies, Lincoln Park, Sunday night, August 25, 1968; tr-268-15 (Box 2)
      Use CD-52
    - Side #1, Box R, Early Riot, Tape #1, Steve Simmons, McCarthy Headquarters, James Butler; Side #2, Tape #3 Sunday night, Yippie Lincoln Park; Tape #2 Grant Park - Sunday Afternoon Demonstration, August 25, 1968.; tr-268-16 (Box 2)
      Use CD-53-54
    - Tape #4 Monday afternoon demonstration to protest arrest of Tom Hayden. Mob, Marshall Monday afternoon, #5 Robert Greenblatt, #T Grape Striker, black panthers; Side #2 Several black interviews; Tuesday afternoon march (pacifist Student Caucus (Conrad Hilton) Linda King, etc. Jackson St. bridge confrontation, mace and gas. Vic Bell Army deserter., August 26, 1968; tr-268-17 (Box 2)
    - Tape #4 Demonstration Monday afternoon, August 26, 1968; tr-268-18 (Box 2)
      Use CD-55
    - Tape #5 Demonstration Monday afternoon, August 26, 1968; tr-268-19 (Box 2)
      Use CD-56
    - Tape #T Grant Park, August 1968; tr-268-20 (Box 2)
      Use CD-57-59
    - Box 10, kneeling in streets, Prayer, August 1968; tr-268-21 (Box 2)
      Use CD-59
    - Hayden: "Streets Belong to the People", August 1968; tr-268-22 (Box 2)
      Use CD-60
    - Chicago T.V. and Radio coverage, August 1968; tr-268-23 (Box 2)
      Use CD-61
    - Chicago Democratic Convention, August 1968; tr-268-24 (Box 2)
    - Friday, noon, Chicago, August 30, 1968; tr-268-25 (Box 2)
    - Tuesday afternoon, Minnesota minister, park, Hare Krishna, etc., August 27, 1968; tr-268-26 (Box 2)
    - Red. riot 1. 22 sec. Prep to violence, 2. 25 sec. middle part. 3 to 15, August 1968; tr-268-27 (Box 2)
      Use CD-62
    - Thursday speakers, August 29, 1968; tr-268-28 (Box 2)
      Use CD-63
    - #B side 1: Grant Park, Tuesday night; Side 2 Grant Park, Wednesday - Yippie, Black., August 27-28, 1968; tr-268-29 (Box 2)
      Use CD-64-65
    - Tape T Grant Park, Dick Gregory, Tom Hayden, August 1968; tr-268-30 (Box 2)
      Use CD-66-67
    - #A Lincoln Park, August 1968; tr-268-31 (Box 2)
      Use CD-68
    - #10 Bridge, Mace, and Poor Peoples Wagon, August 1968; tr-268-32 (Box 2)
      Use CD-69
    - Tape #5 Wed. night Thursday morning. Voting Humphrey wins (Penn) Report from floor news (good) Priest on Humphrey, U.S.A., goodness and God; Good stuff on lake Wednesday, (montage) "Army man barking"; Mark Sommer, Galbraith, montage citizen from Minnesota, N.Y. delegate who refused to show pass, Mother supporting daughter who pissed at jail. Vic Stone, Lowenstein, N.Y. leader for convention, Gore Vidal, postponement, & N.Y. withdraw 1, Cal. delegate, Alabama. Side II, Sonos, O'Dwyer, Norman Mailer, Monique Dyer (Daughter of peace candidate in S. Vietnam), Tom Hayden, Thur. McCarthy's daughter, Ralph Abernathy, Thursday noon., August 28-29, 1968; tr-268-33 (Box 2)
      Use CD-70-73
    - Background, Augusty 1968; tr-268-34 (Box 2)
    - Labeled copy Sidney Lens, Old Union, Hare Krishna, (led by Alan Ginsberg) Jonathan, Northside Ministry and Hippie Priest., tr-268-35 (Box 2)
      Use CD-74
    - #9 Student Caucus (Hilton) Linda King On the bridge mace and gas, (DU), August 1968; tr-2685-36 (Box 2)
      Use CD-75
    - Various aspects and action of the Chicago Convention. Very poor quality. Most about Grant Park happenings., Undated; Cassette tr-268-37 (Box 2)
    - Copy of tr-268 no 8, 14, 15, 22, June 16, 1995; DAT tr-7337 (Box 2)
    - Copy of tr-268-20, June 16, 1995; DAT tr-7338 (Box 2)
    - Copy of tr-268-9, June 16, 1995; DAT tr-7339 (Box 2)
  - Subseries 2. Student Radicalism
    - S.D.S. Election Day Rally Willard Straight Hall, Cornell U., Ithaca, N.Y. Bruce Dancis, Douglas Downd, Dave Burak, Alan Snitow. (Side 1 7/8 ips)., November 5, 1968; tr-268-38 (Box 2)
    - Cambridge Commune, John Heckman, Bob Pearlman, Al Graubner, Abe?, Hiliary Putnam. 1 hr. 30 min., November 17, 1968; tr-268-39 (Box 2)
    - Cambridge Commune. Bob Pearlman, David Heckman (1st speaker), Libby Heckman, Alan Graubard (2nd speaker). Interviewer: Sarah Diamant., November 17, 1968; tr-268-40 (Box 2)
    - Mike Rotkin "Talking Cornell Blues" Ithaca Housing Meeting., Undated; tr-268-41 (Box 2)
    - S.D.S. meeting, R.O.T.C. discussion Tactics raison d'etre, May 9, 1969; tr-268-42 (Box 2)
    - S.D.S. study group with Harry Magdoff, at Magdoff's, Taugannock Blvd., August 22, 1968; tr-268-43 (Box 2)
    - Straight confrontation over draft card burning, March 1967; tr-268-44 (Box 2)
  - Subseries 3. Delano, California Interviews
    - Delano, CA. Sarah Diamant, Jerry Brown, N.F.W.A. organizer., March 17, 1969; tr-268-45 (Box 2)
    - School Board Meeting - Delano, California, March 17, 1969; tr-268-46 (Box 2)
    - "Picnic House" Delano, California - June Brown, Boycott chairman, Elaine Ellenson, March 17, 1969; tr-268-47 (Box 2)
    - Delano California, David Fishlow Malcriado Editor, V.F.W.A. Fred Chavez, Caesar Chavez's nephew, Sr. clas President, Delano H.S., suspended., March 17, 1969; tr-268-48 (Box 2)
    - Caesar Chavez with Sarah Diamant. National Farm Workers, Jerry Brown, Antioch, Cornell, Farm Workers, March 18-19, 1969; tr-268-49 (Box 2)
    - Berkeley, California - Sarah Diamant interviewer. Peter Hunt respondent, lawyer, Antioch, Berkeley., Mar. 20, 1969; tr-268-50 (Box 2)
    - All School Meeting, Starr King Divinity School, Berkeley, (Unitarian Universalist), 10-12 a.m. at Starr King, 21 Le Comte Ave., Berkeley, California, March 20, 1969; tr-268-51 (Box 2)
    - Starr King Divinity School All School Meeting, decision making., Mar. 22, 1969; tr-268-52 (Box 2)
- Series V. Transcripts Made from Reel to Reel Recordings
  - Interview with Sidney Lens at the Democratic Convention by Sarah Diamant - from tr-268-2, August 29, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Brother Jonathan & unidentified interview - from tr-268-2, August 29, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Steve Simmons outside of the Young Citizens for Humphrey Headquarters by Sarah Diamant - from tr-268-13, August 25, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Interview with an unidentified person at McCarthy Headquarters by Sarah Diamant - from tr-268-13, August 25, 1968 (Box 2)
  - James Butler at McCarthy Headquarters by Sarah Diamant - from tr-268-13, August 25, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Chicago Democratic Convention, August 28-29, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Interview with an unidentified person by Sarah Diamant and Robert Greenblatt - from tr-268-32, August 26, 1968 (Box 2)
    Can be used with CD-69
  - S.D.S. Election Day Rally, Willard Straight Hall, Cornell University with Douglas Dowd, David Burak, Bruce Dancis, and Alan Snitow - from tr-268-38, November 5, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Cambridge Commune, with Bob Pearlman, David Heckman, Libby Heckman, Alan Graubard by Sarah Diamant - from tr-268-40, November 17, 1968 (Box 2)
- Series VI. Film (masters, not to be used; use DVD-18)
  Footage on F-159-162 was shot by Ralph and Sarah Diamant and James Sheldon in the streets of Chicago at the time of the Democratic Convention, 1968, in connection with Sarah Diamant's Ph.D. thesis, a case study of student activism at Cornell. This footage has been cut in producing the film "The Streets Belong to the People" (reels 3 and 4).
  Views of Chicago immediately before the riots. About thirty feet showing National Guard at the bridges as seen from both sides of the barricade (quick cuts).
  - Footage used in "The Streets Belong to the People", 16mm F-159 (Box 3)
    Note on canister reads: Ginsberg, Jon Rennie
  - "The Streets Belong to the People" outtakes, 16mm F-160 (Box 3)
  - "The Streets Belong to the People" outtakes, 16mm F-161-162 (Box 4)
  - "The Streets Belong to the People", 16mm F-170 (Box 4)
  - "The Streets Belong to the People", 16mm F-1090-1091 (Box 3)
    2 16mm reels in a single can. From ABC News 20th Century Project
- Series VII. Videos
  - "The Streets Belong to the People" (36.5min version), VHS V-49 (Box 3)
    Videocassette of "The Streets Belong to the People," made from footage shot by Ralph and Sarah Diamant and James Sheldon in the Streets of Chicago during th 1968 Democratic National Convention, in connection with Sarah Diamant's Ph.D. thesis. Includes footage of anti-war protestors speaking about the Vietnam War, non-violent protest, the American political system, Democratic nominees Hubert Humphrey and Eugene McCarthy, and more. Also footage of the resulting clashes between the protestors and the Chicago Police Department and National Guard.